Mahendra Duwal Shrestha

4831 E Summit Cir Apt 136 ● Knoxville, TN 37919 ● (865) 441-7363 ● mduwalsh@vols.utk.edu ● duwal.mahendra@gmail.com

SUMMARY

A software developer with 2.5 years of professional industry experience in C#, Asp.Net, Java, Grails. Proven abilities in analysis, test development and application development in both new and existing projects. 2.5 years of experience in developing mathematical simulation programs involving cluster computations in C.

OBJECTIVE

A software engineering position where I can exploit my skills and experience, and further broaden my knowledge and skills.

EDUCATION

MS in Computer Science, The University of Tennessee, Knoxville, GPA: 3.9 2014-present Major courses taken: Computer Systems Organization, Software Systems, Algorithms, Introduction to Pattern Recognition, Databases and Scripting Languages, Applied Cryptography, Distributed System Algorithms

Thesis: Efficient Simulation Of A Simple Evolutionary System

BE in Electronics and Communication Engineering, Pulchowk

2007-2011

Engineering Campus, Tribhuvan University, Nepal, GPA: 3.8

SKILLS SUMMARY

 Programming Language: 	C, C++, Java, C#, Groovy, Javascript, PHP, Perl, Python
 Web Technologies: 	HTML5, Groovy on Grails, ASP.Net, ASP.Net MVC, Ajax,
	Jquery, JSON, Web services, WCF services, REST, SOAP,
	Hibernate, Entity Framework, LINQ, NUnit, JUnit, Spock,
	Spring MVC
Version Control:	git, SVN
Databases:	MYSQL, MSSQL
• Tools:	Gnuplot, pthreads, CUDA, OpenMP, Hadoop, MATLAB, Visual
	Studio, TFS, Eclipse, IntellijIdea, Net beans, Resharper,
	TortoiseSVN, Emacs, Latex
• SDLC:	Waterfall, Agile Scrum
• Platforms:	Linux, Windows, Unix

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Graduate Teaching / Research Assistant, The University of Tennessee, TN

8/2014 - present

- Graded assignments and projects, and tutored for undergraduate classes 'Algorithm Analysis and Automata' and 'Software Engineering' for academic year 2014 - 2015
- Developed code for simulations of mathematical models and plotting graphs using **C** and **gnuplot** for Dr. Sergey Gavrilets in Ecology and Evolutionary Biology Department for academic year 2014 - 2017
- Used cluster computing for simulations and fixed maintenance issues in the cluster

- Analyzed requirement and estimated time frame working with team and clients
- Developed applications in both Windows platform and Linux platform
- Followed **OOP** paradigm and **agile** scrum methodology in application development
- Developed web applications for health care system management in US using ASP.Net, ASP.Net
 MVC and C# as a member of outsourcing service provider team
- Designed and developed database schema and stored procedures in MSSQL and used LINQ queries with ASP.net MVC
- Developed and maintained US health care system management web application modules using **Grails** framework as a member of Deerwalk's product's team
- Designed and developed database schema, scripts and stored procedures in MYSQL
- Led developer's team for development and optimization of generic **MYSQL** scripts for importing staged data from multiple clients into company's product's database system
- Applied Javascript, Jquery, Ajax in client side scripting
- Generated reports using ItextSharp in .Net framework, and using Jasper and Rendering plug-ins in Grails
- Incorporated unit testing in .Net framework using NUnit, and in Grails using JUnit and Spock
- Employed **Web services** and **WCF services** with .Net application and **REST** service with Grails application

PROJECTS

- Thesis on 'Efficient Simulation Of A Simple Evolutionary System' where we provide efficient
 computing methods for genetic algorithm using diploid population model and use it to analyze
 different behavior of genetic algorithm through simulations.
- Designed and developed mini shell system using **C** as part of requirement of graduate class
- Designed and developed program for simulation of different levels of cache and cache operations
- Used **CUDA** to develop Conway's Game of Life as part of GPU project
- Developed Java programs to implement **Hadoop**'s MapReduce technique
- Implemented MPP, KNN, clustering, decision tree, neural networks using C++ and MATLAB in pattern recognition projects
- Designed and developed implementation of case study "The University Accommodation Office Case Study" in MYSQL
- Designed and developed radio frequency linked heart beat monitor and remote data logger as part
 of final project in undergraduate using photo transistor transceiver, micro-controller, RF
 transceiver and MATLAB